Guide to the Judith Rosen Collection ARS.0032
Archive of Recorded Sound
Judith Rosen Collection
1971-2000
ARS.0032
Rosen, Judith
7 boxes: 236 audiocassettes; thee DATs
Archive of Recorded Sound
The Judith Rosen Collection consists of unpublished recordings on audiotape featuring performances, lectures, and radio programs concerning classical music, with a particular focus on twentieth century composition, as well as women musicians and composers.
Access
Open for research; material must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use. Contact the Archive for assistance.
Source
The Judith Rosen Collection was donated to the Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound by Judith Rosen in 2008.
Scope and Contents
The Judith Rosen Collection consists of music researcher and author Judith Rosen's personal collection of audiocassette recordings, many of which are unpublished. Rosen, who has written a highly-regarded biography of composer Grazyna Bacewicz, as well as articles for High Fidelity/Musical America and the New Grove series, is a current or former board member of The Women's Philharmonic, Women's Philharmonic Advocacy, the Arnold Schoenberg Institute, the Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra, and the Ojai Music Festival. While there is a mix of styles in the collection's music performances, the majority is new music and the work of twentieth century composers. Given her association with the Women's Philharmonic, it is no surprise that the collection is also strong on women composers and musicians. Among the live and studio recordings that comprise the majority of the collection, there are radio programs, interviews, and conference presentations. Many appear to be promotional demos and other semi-commercial issues. Original sources are rarely credited, and some tapes may be copies of commercially released material. There are a handful of published cassettes retained in the collection as well. The tapes have been alphabetized, for the most part by composer.
Perhaps the most significant recordings here are from the Freeman Musicale series of lecture/performances named for philanthropist Betty Freeman. These salons (also known as the Music Room sessions) took place both in Freeman's home in Beverly Hills and later at the Rosen's in Encino, and featured many of the leading lights in the contemporary composition world, from Elliot Carter, Pierre Boulez and Sylvano Bussotti to Gyorgy Ligeti, Mel Powell, and Roger Reynolds, even jazz musician Anthony Braxton. Other recordings in the collection were commissions by Freeman, such as Kaija Saariaho's opera L'Amour de Loin. The collection also contains lectures from the National Congress on Women in Music, various interviews with the Seeger family (Barbara, Charles, Mike, Peggy) about Ruth Crawford Seeger, and several recordings of Rosen herself in lectures or interviews, as well as her husband Ron Rosen's Sixtieth Birthday Concert featuring premiered works by William Kraft, Leonard Rosenman and Vernon Duke.
- John Adams, Naive and Sentimental Music, 1999; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Amy Beach, Sonata in A Minor; G. Bacewicz, Sonata No.4. Duo Pontremoli, 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- A.M.C. Beach. Symphony in E, Gaelic. Karl Kreuger & Royal Philharmonic, 1968; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Grazyna Bacewicz, 2nd Piano Sonata. Leslie Pettys, 1984-01-25; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Grazyna Bacewicz, IV Sonata; Amy Beach, Sonate. Pontremolis. Severance Hall, 1991-08-26; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Grazyna Bacewicz, Sonatas. Belnick-Silvansky, 1947; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Berio, 2 audiocassettes (Audio 1)
- Betty and Henry, Family Tree, 1984-12-10; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Marilyn Bliss interview by Cynthia Bell. WBAI, Hear and Now, 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Victoria Bond, Luncheon at Music Center, 1972-04-03; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Victoria Bond, Urban Bird, 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Boulez with Chowning (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1992-05-17; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Music of Paul Bowles. Irene Hermann, 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Anthony Braxton (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Brendel lecture at Schoenberg Institute, 1988-05-02; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Jane Brockman, Perihelion. Arioso String Orchestra, 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Joanna Bruzdowicz. Film Music Demo, 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Joanna Bruzdowicz. Four Seasons' Greetings. Live recording, Poznan, Poland, 1989-01-04; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Joanna Bruzdowicz (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1992-12-06; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Joanna Bruzdowicz. Varsovia String Quartet, 1989-03; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Sylvano Bussotti (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1991-12-01; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Cal Arts Lecture, 1992-11-18; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Wendy Carlos on NPR Weekend Edition, 1992-08-09; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Elliott Carter (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1994-01-12; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Gloria Cheng-Cochran, 1997-11-18; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Chen Yi, Chamber Music, 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Chen Yi, Concerto For Cello and Orchestra. Glen Barton Cortese, Manhattan Symphony Orchestra, Paul Tobias, 1999-05; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
  Chen, Yi, 1953-
- Chen Yi, Orchestral Music, 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Chen Yi, Recent Works, 1994; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Cloud Zymurgy. Music For Women Composers, 1973-08-04; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Contempo Ensemble - Musica Elettroacustica da Camera, 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Gloria Coutes, 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Cindy Cox. Sonnets to Orpheus; Woven Rains, 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Kui Dong. CCRMA/Stanford University, 1 audiocassette (Audio 1)
- Paul Dresher Ensemble, Power Failure. Live, Minneapolis. Text by Rinde Eckert, 1989-11; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Charles Dvorak, piano and violin compositions. Recorded at Capitol Records, Hollywood, 1992-09-28; 2 audiocassettes (Audio 2)
- Music of Veronica Elsea, 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Siegrid Ernst, 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Eskin – Women Composers Church Program, 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Eskin-Babcock-Speaker Trio. Gardner Museum. Women Composers, 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Jed Feuer, Reactions for Wind Quintet. Stockhausen Wind Ensemble, 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Nancy Fierro and Bonnie Grice interview, part, 1993-03; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Sarah Fishko, Michael Rabin radio program, WNYC, 1999; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Flaherty. Flute Concerto; Oboe Quartet; Upon the Cello, 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Tom Flaherty Recital, 1990-03-25; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Tsippi Fleischer, Oratorio, 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Foss, Concerto Left Hand. Fleisher, Piano. Tanglewood Orchestra, Ozawa, Conductor, 1994-07-23; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Kenneth Frazelle, The Motion of Stone. Boston University Chamber Chorus and Gardner Chamber Orchestra, 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Kenneth Frazelle, Selected Works, 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Tania Gabrielle French, Composer, 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Ada Gentile, Criptografia, 1986-02; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Pia Gilbert, Gestures. Cincinnati Philharmonia, Gerhard Samuel, conductor, 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Jamie Giteck, Om Shanti. Music and Healing Series I. Thomasa Eckert, soprano, New Performance Group. Recorded at the Nippon Kan Theater, Seattle, 1989-05; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Giteck. Breathing Songs From a Turning Sky. New Music Ensemble, SF Conservatory 4/18/80; Thunder, Like a White Bear Dancing. Eckert/Nelson/Lenoir. Belgian Radio 3/78, 1978-1980; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Alexander Goehr (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1992-12-06; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Gubaidulina, Two Paths. NY Philharmonic, 1999-05-01; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Stephen Hartke, Violin Concerto; Symphony No.2. Riverside Symphony, George Rothman, conductor, 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Stephen Hartke, The King of the Sun. Los Angeles Piano Quartet, 92nd Street YMCA, NYC, 1990-02-13; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Stephen Hartke, The Ascent of the Equestrian in a Balloon. National Symphony Orchestra, Leonard Slatkin; Wulfstan at the Millenium. Parnassus, Anthony Korf, 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Stephen Hartke, Alvorada. Pasadena Chamber Orchestra, Robert Duerr, 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Stephen Hartke (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1991-10-11; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Jonathan Harvey (dub of Bridge BCD 9031), 1992; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Hans Werner Henze, Quintet for Piano, Two Violins, Viola and Violincello. Guarneri String Qaurtet, Peter Serkin. UCLA, 1993-03-23; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Holocaust Memorial Concert, Gindi Auditorium, 1987-04-26; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Katherine Hoover, Double Concerto. Bach Ensemble of Baltimore, conducted by Paul Mori, 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Katherine Hoover: Double Concerto; Elinor Armer: New Work for S.F. Girls Chorus., 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Joan Huang (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1992-10-25; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Compositions by Joan Huang, 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Joan Huang-Kraft. Yellow Land; Three Images of Tang, 1 audiocassette (Audio 2)
- Deniz Ince, Copper Sky, 1 audiocassette folders (Audio 3)
- Tape for International Alliance for Women in Music (IAWM). Sidney Robertson Cowell on RCS 12/14/82; Pete 12/8/82; Rabbit Songs, 1997; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- International Alliance for Women in Music. Nancy Fierro on Hildegarde, IAWM Conference, 1997-06-01; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- Piano works by Japanese women composers. Kurimoto, Yoko; Mori, Junko, 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- Vitezslava Kapralova, 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- Aaron Jay Kernis, Symphony in Waves (Schirmer), 1 audiocassette folders (Audio 3)
- Aaron Jay Kernis, String Quartet “Musica Celestas.” Lark String Quartet, 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- Kernis, Double Concerto. St. Paul (Schirmer), 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- Guy Klucevsek, Blue Window (Zoar ZCS-8). Klucevsek; Teiji Ito/Johann Strauss, Jr.; John Zorn; Pauline Oliveros; Lois V. Vierk, 1986; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- B. Kolb. All in Good Time. Long Beach Symphony, May 31, 1997. Commissioned by NY Philharmonic for 50th Anniversary; Voyants, Ensemble 20 Jahrhundert, Austrian Radio, October 15, 1992, 1992-1997; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- William Kraft. Settings from Pierrot Lunaire (1987-90); Concerto for Percussion and Chamber Ensemble (1993), 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- William Kraft. Songs of Flowers Bells and Death (1991); Music for String Quartet & Percussion (1993), 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- William Kraft. Encounters X (1992); Symphony of Sorrows (1995), 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- William Kraft. Gallery 4-5 (1985); Episodes for violin and piano (1987), 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- William Kraft (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1991-12-01; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- JoAnn Kuchera-Morin, Tachyons. LA Philharmonic and Santa Barbara Symphony, conducted by Varujan Kojian, 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- JoAnn Kuchera-Morin, Yugen for solo clarinet, 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- JoAnn Kuchera-Morin, Concerto For Clarinet and Clarinets, 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- JoAnn Kuchera-Morin, Dreampaths, 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- Hanna Kulenty, Piano Concerto No. 2 (1991). National Philharmonic Orchestra, conducted by Ives Prin, 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- Hanna Kulenty. Air; Cannon; Sesto; Still Life With a Violin; Arcus, 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- Hanna Kulenty, Violin Concerto for Chamber Orchestra; G. Bacewicz, String Quartet No.6, 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- Bun-Ching Lam, Impetus for Chinese Orchestra, 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- Larsen, Symphony; Water Music; Up Where The Air Gets Thin; Tom Twist; Four on the Floor, 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- Libby Larsen and Cage tribute (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1992-10-04; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- Morton Lauridsen, 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- Anne LeBaron, Strange Attractors. New Orchestral Reading Project, David Gilbert, conductor, 1989-02; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- Lefanu. Old Woman; Penny for a Song, 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- Tania Leon. Indigena; Carabali, 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- Tania Leon. Kabiosile, American Composers Orchestra, Dennis Russell Davies, conductor, Ursula Oppens, soloist; Bata, Bay Area Women's Philharmonic, Joann Falletta, conductor (Peer Music), 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- A Portrait of Rosina Lhevinne I-IV, created by Salome Arkatov, KUSC, 1980; 4.0 audiocassette(s) (Audio 3)
- Gyorgy Ligeti, Merkin Hall Concert, New York, 1986-11-12; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- Gyorgy Ligeti (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1993-02-28; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3)
- Annea Lockwood. Thousand Years Dreaming; Night and Fog; Red Mesa, 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Annea Lockwood and Others (The Aerial #2, Spring 1990), 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Lockwood, World Rhythms; Anderson, Points; Spiegel, Expanding Universe, 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Lutoslawski, LAPO, 1993-02-07; 2 audiocassettes (Audio 4)
- Elizabeth Macready, Serenata Concertante; Symphony for Double String Orchestra, 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- A. Mahler; V. Kapralova; G. Mucha. Women in Love. Jill Gomez and John Constable, 1987-04-28; 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Alma Mahler, Four Early Songs. Mufrieda Bell, 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Ursula Mamlok. Constellations, San Francisco Symphony, Blomstedt, conductor. Broadcast 2/22/94; Girasol, Parnassus, A. Korg, conductor 9/30/92, 1992-1994; 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Bunita Marcus. Adam and Eve (1987), The Rugmaker (1986), Music for Japan (1983), 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Silumia Milstein, 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Mary Carr Moore's David Rizzio, KPFK, 1982-04-18; 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Music By Women Composers. Elizabeth Jacquet de la Guerra; Wilhelmme von Bayreuth, 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- John Naples, Selections and Excerpts, 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Roger Neill, Riverside Symphony International Composer Reading, 1994-02; 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Gladys Nordenstrom, Work for Orchestra III. Winterthur Orchestra, Switzerland, 1975-09-17; 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Jocy de Oliveros, 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Pauline Owens 85th Birthday Party at Red Lion Inn, San Jose. Messages for Betty, 1987-10-18; 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Hilda Paredes, 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Wayne Peterson. The Face of the Night; The Heart of the Dark; The Widening Gyre, 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Wayne Peterson, Capriccio for Flute and Piano (1972), 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- George Perle, Piano Concerto No.2 (1992). Utah Symphony, Joseph Silverstein, conductor, Michael Boriskin, piano, 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Vivian Perlis Interview Re: Schoenberg Institute by Judith Rosen, 1997-12-14; 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Alexander Pierre, Symphony No.2, op.74, 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Bill Powell, Clarinet Works by Women Composers. KUSC, 1990-03-18; 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Mel Powell Interview by Gail Eichenthal. KUSC, 1989-06-05; 2 audiocassettes (Audio 4)
- Mel Powell (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1992-10-25; 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Mel Powell, Duplicates. World Premiere. Los Angeles Philharmonic, David Alan Miller, conductor. Robert Taub, Alan Feinberg, pianists, 1990-01-26; 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Marta Ptaszynska, Holocaust Memorial Cantata. Lira Singers, P. Dijkstra, piano, D. Clouser, S. Przyrzycki. Lucy Ding, conductor. North Shore Congregation Israel, Chicago. live recording by WFMT, 1992-04-05; 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Shulamit Ran phone interview, 1993-05; 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Shulamit Ran. Da Capo Chamber Players (dub of Bridge CD), 1995; 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Shulamit Ran (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1993-05-16; 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Bernard Rands (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1994-02-27; 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Bernard Rands, Canti Dell'Eclisse (1988); John Harbison, The Flight into Egypt (1986), Gli Accordi Piu Sati (1993). LACO, C. Perick, conductor, 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Roger Reynolds (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1993-04-25; 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Reynolds, Symphony [The Stages of Life]. Los Angeles Philharmonic, Esa-Pekka Salonen, conductor, 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Marga Richter interview, 1983-02-22; 1 audiocassette (Audio 4)
- Marga Richter, Into My Heart. Georgia State University Choral Society, Lynn Schenbeck, conductor, 1991-04-05; 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Music By Marga Richter #2, 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Marga Richter. Lament. Izler Solomon, conductor; Concerto for Piano and Violas, Cellos and Basses. William Masselos, piano; Carlos Surinach, condcutor, 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Eliane Robert-George, 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Eliane Robert-George, Passionis, 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Carlos Rodriguez (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1991-11-10; 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Carlos Rodriguez. Concert music selections. Los Angeles Philharmonic Institute Orchestra, Keith Lockhart, conductor, 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Carlos Rodriguez. Five movements for solo amplified/processed flute; In solid motion, 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Carlos Rodriguez, Variations on a Theme by Francois Couperin, 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Carlos Rodriguez. Nightsongs; This Poet Bukowski, 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Marela Rodriguez, Concert for Recorders - Mexico. American Composers' Orchestra, D. Russell Davies, conductor, 1994-02; 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Ned Rorem, More Than A Day. LACO, Yoav Talmi, conductor, 1995-11-03; 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Judith Rosen, Hunter College, 1985-04-15; 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Judith Rosen Interviews Ruth and Annea [Lockwood?] for Panel Inclusion, 1984-04-23; 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Judith Rosen, Nancy Fierro. On Bacewics, 1982-02-03; 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Ron Rosen's 60th Birthday Concert. Bill Kraft, Cadeon. Dorothy Stone, flute; Gloria Cheng, piano. Leonard Rosenman, Theme and Elaborations. Rene Mendel, violin; Scott Dunn, piano. Vernon Duke, songs. Kay Vernon Ingalls. Encino, California, at Rosens, 1992-07-22; 1 DAT (Audio 7)
- Leonard Rosenman. Chamber Music IV, LA Chamber Orchestra; Exposition and Elaborations, Scott Dunn and Rene Mandel, 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Leonard Rosenman (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1993-04-25; 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Rosenman, Theme and Elaborations. Scott Dunn, Rene Mandel, 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Daniel Rothman. Chamber Ensemble Music; Piano Music. Bernhard Wambach, 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Christopher Rouse (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1992-02-02; 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Anna Rubin. Freedom, Sweet and Bitter. National Orchestral Association, Jorge Mester, conductor, 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Anna Rubin, Seachange, 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Anna Rubin, Remembering. Judith Kellock, Karl Paulnack. Ithaca College, 1993-09-11; 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Anna Rubin on Fanny Mendelssohn. Cal Arts KPFK Tape II, 1974-05-30; 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Dane Rudhyar KPFK Broadcast, 1974-01-30; 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Kaija Saariaho, L'Amour De Loin. SW German Radio Orchestra, Schoenberg Chorus. Flanders Festival, Brussels, 2000-09; 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Aulis Sallinen (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1992-02-23; 2 audiocassettes (Audio 5)
- Esa-Pekka Salonen (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1994-04-17; 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Valerie Samson. Night Visits; Blue Territory II; Montage, 1 audiocassette folders (Audio 5)
- Rhian Samuel. The White Amaryllis; Shadow Dance, 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Felicia Sandler. Orual and Psyche; Spring and Fall; The Cat, 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Schoenberg on NPR. ASI and USC Lawsuit, 1996-06; 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Legacy of Arnold Schoenberg on KUSC, with Paul Zukofsky, 1993-01-04; 2 audiocassettes (Audio 5)
- Schoenberg String Quartet, Bill McGlaughlin. St. Paul Sunday Morning, Minnesota Public Radio, 1991-04-28; 1 audiocassette (Audio 5)
- Stefano Scodanibbio, 1993-12-05; 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Barbara Seeger interview by Judith Rosen. Riverside, California, 1984-12-15; 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Charles Seeger, Dictated Answers to Questions about Ruth Crawford Seeger's Compositional Activity 1929-1953, 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Mike Seeger interview by Barbara Jepson, 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Peggy Seeger interview, Wigmore Hall, 1972-02; 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Seeger, Maconchy Interviews, 1972-02-21; 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Liz Shropshire, 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Sheila Silver, Chariessa, 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Sheila Silver, Song of Sarah (Sharat Sarah), 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Sheila Silver, Shirat Silver, 1987; 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Sheila Silver, Dance Converging, 1987; 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Sheila Silver, Sonata for Cello and Piano, 1988; 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Sheila Silver, To The Spirit Unconquered, 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Dame Ethyl Smyth. Beechham on Smyth; Smyth's March of the Women; Smyth on Brahms, BBC, 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Kathleen St. John, 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Steiger. Quintessence; Dialogues II, 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Steiger. Hexadecathalon; Dialogues III; Tributaries for Nancarrow, 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Steven Stucky (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1993-05-16; 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Sutherland, The Young Kubbarli; Snyder. Buffalo Grass, Fireweed Concerto, 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Erzsebet Szonyi; Jana Obrovska, 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Maria Agata Szymanowska. The Polish Music Reference Center at USC presents Music of Polish Woman Composers, 1993-03-13; 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Tailleferre. Ruth Ehrlich, violin; Marcia Eckert, piano, 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Tan Dun, A Collection of Orchestral Works (China Record Company AL-53), 1986; 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Elias Tanenbaum, Kaleidoscope. American Composers Orchestra, 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Augusta Read Thomas (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1994-02-27; 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Augusta Read Thomas, Words Of The Sea. Commissioned and premiered by Chicago Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Pierre Boulez, 1996-12-12; 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Music by Augusta Read Thomas, Tania Leon, and Emma Lou Dieymer, 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Augusta Read Thomas, 3 audiocassettes (Audio 6)
- Michael Torke. Copper; Adjustable Wrench; Yellow Pages; Vanada; Ecstatic Orange, 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Tower, Piano Concerto. Ursula Oppert, 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Rozlyn Tureck, 1981-03; 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Berthold Tuercke. Oktett; Absence. Berlin Ensemble, Tuercke, conductor, 1991-02-17; 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Jan Vandervelde; Emma Lou Diemer, 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Lois V. Vierk, Go Guitars, 1 audiocassette (Audio 6)
- Lois Vierk. Song for 3 Clarinets, Inverted Fountain; Women Orchestra Conductors, First National Congress, 1 audiocassette (Audio 7)
- Joelle Wallach, Orison of Ste. Theresa, 1 audiocassette (Audio 7)
- Melinda Wagner, Falling Angels. Commissioned for Chicago Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Daniel Barenboim, 1 audiocassette (Audio 7)
- Joelle Wallach, Oneiros, The Dream. American Chamber Ensemble, 1 audiocassette (Audio 7)
- Weir, Turke, Korde, Krenek, Webern. USC CME, Crockett, conductor, 1991-02-26; 1 audiocassette (Audio 7)
- Judith Weir, Sederunt Principes; Distance and Enchantment, 1 audiocassette (Audio 7)
- Judith Weir, Heroic Strokes of the Bow; Arnamurchan Point, 1 audiocassette (Audio 7)
- Olly Wilson (Freeman Musicale Archives), 1992-02-02; 1 audiocassette (Audio 7)
- Olly Wilson, Sinfonia, 1 audiocassette (Audio 7)
- Olly Wilson, Trio for Violin, Cello and Piano. Griffin Music Ensemble, 1989-09-26; 1 audiocassette (Audio 7)
- Women Composers of Electronic Music, First National Congress on Women in Music, 1981-03; 1 audiocassette (Audio 7)
- Women Composers of Electronic and Computer Music. First National Congress on Women in Music, 1 audiocassette (Audio 7)
- Women Orchestra Conductors, First National Congress on Women in Music, 1981-11-11; 1 audiocassette (Audio 7)
  Duplicate note